startupbootcamp.org 2017-02-11

# Privacy policy - Startupbootcamp

This application (hereinafter “Application”) collects some Personal Data from its Users.

The Data are collected and processed for the purposes set out below.

## Data Processing Ownership

Startupbootcamp Holding Ltd – London (UK),  
privacy@startupbootcamp.org

## Types of Data collected

Among the Data that this Application may collect there are: Cookie, Browsing and usage Data and Email.

Other Personal Data collected may be highlighted by other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text, in the moment when the Data collection happens.  
The Personal Data may be freely inserted by the User or the Data Subject, or collected automatically when using the Application.  
Any use of Cookies by the Application or the owners of third party services used by the Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify the User and remember his/her preferences for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data, in particular Navigation Data, by deactivating the Application’s Cookies may make it impossible to surf or for the Application to provide its services.

The Personal Data collected may regard both the User and third parties whose data the User provides.  
The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through the Application and declares that (s)he has the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Owner of all responsibility towards third parties.

## Mode and place of processing the Data obtained

### Method of Processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of the Interested Parties and Users in a lawful and proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification or unauthorized destruction of the Data. Processing is carried out using computers and / or telematic means, with organizational methods and logics strictly related to the stated purposes.  
In addition to the owner, in some cases, access to the Data may be available to external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies). The updated list of Managers may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Place

The Data are processed at the headquarters of the Data Controller, unless stated otherwise in the rest of this document.

### Conservation Time

The Data are kept for the time necessary to perform the service requested by the User, and the User can always ask for their suspension or removal.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User or the Data Subject are collected for the following purposes: Analytics, Managing email addresses and sending messages, Interaction with external social networks and platforms and Content commenting.

The kinds of Personal Data used for each purpose are given in the specific sections of this document.

The use of Data for additional purposes by the Owner may in some cases, and for legal purposes, require specific consent by the User or the Data Subject.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data and the services provided by third parties

Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine Application use, to prepare reports on an Application’s activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Managing email addresses and sending messages

These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts to communicate with the User via email.  
The services are used to collect data concerning the date and time when the mail is viewed by the User, as well as when the user interacts with incoming mail, such as by clicking on links included in the email.

#### Mailchimp (Mailchimp)

Mailchimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by Mailchimp Inc.

Personal data collected: Email.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the Application’s pages.  
The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php)

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of the Application.  
Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.  
If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when users do not use the content commenting service.

#### Disqus (Disqus)

Disqus is a content commenting service provided by Big Heads Labs Inc.

Personal data collected: Cookie and Browsing and usage Data.

Place of Processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://docs.disqus.com/help/30/)

## Additional information about data processing

### Legal Protection

The User’s Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner of the Application in court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from its improper use or that of related services by the User.

### Additional Information

Specific information may be shown on the pages of the Site concerning particular services or the processing of Data provided by the User or by the Data Subject.

### Maintenance

The User’s Personal Data may be further used in ways and for purposes required for Application maintenance.

### System Logs

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services it uses may collect system logs, i.e., files that record interaction – including navigation. They may also contain personal data, such as IP addresses.

### Information not contained in this policy

More information on processing Personal Information may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### The Rights of Data Subjects

Those persons to whom the Data refer have the right, at any time, to know whether their data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Owner of the Processing System.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Application reserves the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page, and by ensuring analogous protection of the Personal Information in all cases. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom.

### Information about this privacy policy

This privacy policy was prepared autonomously and with full assumption of responsibility by the Owner of the Personal Data, taking the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on the Iubenda servers as a starting point.

### Definitions and legal references

#### Personal information or Data

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Browsing and usage Data

Information collected automatically from the Site, including the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the users who connect to the site, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server’s answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the visitor, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page) and the details about the path followed within the site with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the operating system and the user’s IT environment.

#### User

Means the individual user of the Application’s services or products.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refer.

#### Data Processor

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other organization, association or organization designated by the Data Controller for the Personal Data processing system.

#### Data Controller

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Site.

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy exclusively regards this Application.

Latest update: December 01, 2012
